Brian Dennis Curran Jr.

610-246-9226 | <u>bdc291@msstate.edu</u> | West Grove, PA 19390 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brian-dennis-curran-jr/

Summary

Brian is a senior Computer Science major at Mississippi State University with experience in Software Development, Research and Development, Quality Assurance, and Automation. He has spent the last four years as a student, researcher, intern, and cadet; gaining experience with numerous facets of software development and software technologies.

Core Competencies

Scripting, Automated Software Testing, Software Quality Assurance, Software R&D, Software Documentation, Leadership, Vehicular Architecture.

Experience

Center for Advanced Vehicular Systems, Starkville, MS Undergraduate Researcher

February 2016—Present

I work part time with a team of research associates and undergraduate/graduate researchers in the research and development of vehicular propulsion system simulation software for the Army Corps of Engineers.

- Perform data analysis to ensure that propulsion system simulations yield reliable, valid, and consistent results.
- Quality Assurance of software to find and debug issues in the application.
- Wrote variable dependency analysis script to analyze thousands of lines of Matlab code and extract important lines based on the changing of a given initialization variable. This is used to scale initialization data.
- Created unit test suite for testing of resource functions of dependency analysis script.
- Assisted in writing a script to automatically plot hundreds of graphs using GNUPlot.
- Wrote several Makefiles for the construction of our C++ code.

Fortna, Chadds Ford, PA

Software Intern

June 2014—August 2017

I worked as a software intern during the summers/winters doing a variety of tasks, such as writing automated test cases/suites to test our warehouse software, software deployments, documentation, scripting to automate various processes, among many other tasks.

- Wrote python and bash scripts to automate numerous redundant processes.
- Performed Redhat software deployments to both internal and production environments.
- Wrote numerous automated test cases using Robot Framework.
- Documented procedures for doing software deployments as well as how to write Robot Framework test suites/cases.
- Built a pick-put rack (configuration on network, wiring, construction, interfacing) for use in testing our warehouse execution system.
- Took lead role in writing test suites to test the end-to-end flow of packages in our warehouse software for major distribution center project.
- Taught new interns and entry level Software QA Engineers the basics of Fortna WCS/OM and how to utilize Robot Framework for automated testing.
- Collaborated with colleagues in research of prospective testing methodologies for our JEE code.
- Learned basics of scripting, automated software testing.

Brian Dennis Curran Jr.

United States Air Force, Mississippi State University

December 2015—Present

Air Force ROTC Cadet

Currently a cadet in Air Force ROTC. Upon graduation, prospective AFSC is Cyber Operations.

- Gained leadership experience through leading subordinates to accomplish tasks in cadet wing.
- Public speaking experience through briefing cadet wing.

Education

Mississippi State University, Starkville, MS B.S. in Computer Science

2014-2019

Accumulative GPA: 3.97Minor: Aerospace Studies

References

1. Greg Henley

Research Engineer Center for Advanced Vehicular Systems: Mississippi State University Cell: 662-312-1307 | Office: 662-325-4587

henley@cavs.msstate.edu

2. Daniel Avram

Software Engineer Fortna

Cell: 610-406-3687

daniel.e.avram@gmail.com